welcome back.  I'm back.
お帰りなさい。ただいまです。
Well, I think he came back to Japan from Mexico.
あの、ま、メキシコから日本に帰ってきたと思うんですけどうん。
Um, what was something you wanted to eat in Japan, or something you ate that was really delicious?
あの、日本で食べたかったものとか食べてめっちゃ美味しかったものって何ですか?
Wow.  Well, of course, sushi.
うわあ。えっとね、ま、もちろんですけど、お寿司。
Yeah.  Ah, sushi.  Sushi.  Wow.
うん。あ、寿司。お寿司。へえ。
Well, there's a wide variety, isn't there?
ま、あの、種類が豊富じゃないですか?
Yes.  Yeah.  Yeah.
うん。うん。うん。
So it's still fun.  Even at conveyor belt sushi restaurants.
だからやっぱ楽しめるだ。回転寿司とかでも
Oh, right.  sorry.  Yeah.  yes.
あ、そう。ごめんなさい。うん。はい。
Conveyor belt sushi is really delicious.
回転寿司すごい美味しいですよね。
No, I see.
いや、そうですか。
Well, how can I put it? The quality of the conveyor belt sushi is high.  It seems to be getting more expensive every year.
いや、なんか、なんて言うんですか?回転寿司クオリティ高い。なんか年々高くなってる気がする。
Oh, I see.  Well, what was particularly delicious?
ああ、そうですか。え、特に何が美味しかったですか?
Well, something like that
ええ、なんかそれこそ
.
うん。
Well, regular fish, like tuna and things like that are delicious too.  Of course, it
ね、普通のお魚だったりとか、あの、マグロとかああいうのとかも美味しい。もちろん
's not like a real sushi restaurant.
本当のお寿司屋さんとは違うじゃないですか。
Yeah.  Yeah.   I
うん。うん。
mean, conveyor belt sushi is
なんかあれもう回転寿司ってこう
like cup ramen.
ラーメンで言うカップラーメンみたいな。
Ah, that's right.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.  It was really delicious.
ああ、そうですよね。うん。うん。うん。うん。すごい美味しかった。
Wow.  Sushi is definitely the best.
へえ。やっぱお寿司が1番。
yes.  Also, I went back to my hometown this time, yeah yeah yeah.  yes.
そう。あとあの僕今回地元に帰ってたんですけどうんうんうん。はい。
Yes, in the neighborhood.  It's great that there's a
近所にはい。もう30
yakitori restaurant that's been in business for over 30 years
年以上続く焼き鳥屋さんがあって
.
かいいですね。
oh yeah.  This is a place I've been going to since I was a child
そうそう。こ子供の頃からずっと行ってたとこなんですけど
.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yes there.   It
うん。うん。うん。そこはねはい。
's delicious as expected.
やっぱ美味しいですね。
Wow.  So, is there a counter? Yes,
へえ。で、カウンターがあるんですか?
there is a counter, so it really is like a tatami room
カウンターがあって、もう本当に座敷に
.
うん。
Well, I'd
ね、座敷があって、テーブルが2
like to have a tatami room with two tables.   It
つあってみたいな。
really is a stale feeling.  Yes, yes, yes.
もう本当ね、染みったれた感じの。そう、そう、そう。
Wow.  I see.  What do you drink at times like that, Yusuke? You like alcohol, don't you?
へえ。そっか。そういう時ってゆ介さん何飲むんですか?お酒好きですよね。確か
I definitely like it.  I've been drinking beer all this time.
僕好きです。ずっとビール飲んでます。
Oh, beer? I
あ、ビールなんですか?
love beer.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.
ビール大好きね。うん。うん。うん。
So, are Japanese beer and Mexican beer really different? Completely different.   Isn't that
え、やっぱ日本のビールとメキシコのビールは違いますか?全然違います。
right?
違いますか?
Mexican beer is really easy to drink.  How do you say it? Just a little bit like drinking a carbonated drink.
メキシコのビールってすごいなんか飲みやすい。ちょっとなんて言うんですか?炭酸飲料のちょっとお酒履いてるぐらい。
Really? Yes, yes, yes, yes.
本当ですか?そう、そう、そう、そう。
Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.  That's about it.
うん。うん。うん。そんな感じですけど。
Yeah.  Japanese beer has a stronger flavor, so it really
うん。日本のビールはもっとこう味が強くてね、
feels like you're drinking beer.
ビール飲んでるなっていう感じ。
Yeah.  Oh, does it have a strong flavor?
うん。え、味強いんですか?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.   I guess that's what it means
ええ、そう、そう、そう、そう。
.  But when you say that, I'm like,
ていうのかな。でもそんな言うて僕あの
yeah, yeah.   The
うんうん。
lower one isn't higher, so even if I closed my eyes and asked which one was Mexican beer and which one was Japanese beer, I'm not sure I could guess.
下が超えてるわけじゃないので多分目つぶってどっちがメキシコのビール、どっちがね、日本のビールっていうやっても多分もしかしたら当てられる自信ないです。
Oh, I see.
ああ、そうですか。
Yes, I see.  I see.
ええ、そっか。そっか。
Ah, so in Japan, I
あ、じゃあ日本では、
was impressed by the sushi and yakitori.   The
ま、寿司と焼き鳥に感動した。
yakitori was amazing.  Oh, and of course the ramen was delicious too.  Yeah.
焼き鳥、感動しましたね。あ、もちろんラーメンも美味しかったです。うん。
Wow.  Well, when
へえ。え、なんか
I was a student, there was a
僕その学生時代に
ramen restaurant that I used to go to often, not every day, but yes
やっぱ毎日、毎日ではないですけど、よく行っていたラーメン屋さんがあって
.  Yeah.  That's the kind of place it is.   It's
うん。うん。そういうところってうん。
nostalgic, delicious and just the best.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.
懐かしさプラスやっぱ美味しいプラスで最高じゃないですか。うん。うん。うん。
So, is there a place like that? Like a place that I used to frequent.   It was my
さ、そういうとこあります?こう行きつけだったところで。
favorite place.  I actually like to try new stores all the time
行きつけだったとこ。私結構いつも新しいお店に行くのが好きで
.  Yeah.  No, I don't.
うん。うん。ないですね。
Oh, I see.  Oh, you're quite
あ、そっか。え、やぱ結構
adventurous when it comes to menus. Do you like to experiment?
メニューも冒険するの好きですか?
Hmm.
うーん。
Instead of ordering the standard, I order the recommendation of the day.
定番とかではなく本日のおすすめとかを頼んだりとか。
Yeah.  Ah, but if it's an ingredient I like, I'll order it.
うん。ああ、でも自分が好きな食材だったらそれを頼みます。
oh.  Oh, what do you like? Like skirt steak.
おお。え、何が好き?ハラミとか。
Oh, like ham.  The ribs and meat?
あ、ハミとか。ハみとお肉か。
Maybe meat or something.  Oh, there are cherry blossoms.  Yeah.
肉とかなんだろう。あ、桜ある。うん。
Yeah.  Yeah.
うん。うん。
Well, what else is there? I love skirt steak.  Skirt steak.
えっと、あとは何がありますかね?もうハラミ好きですね。ハラミ。
Yeah.
うん。
Yakiniku? Yakiniku.  Yakiniku
焼肉か?焼肉。焼肉かね
maybe?  Yusuke, didn't you eat yakiniku? I did
え。ゆ介さん焼肉食べなかったんですか?
eat yakiniku.  I ate it.  I ate it.
焼肉食べましたよ。食べました。食べまし。
What do you think? It's different from Mexican meat.
どうですか?メキシカの肉と違います。
Ah, they're both delicious, but maybe they're just different.
ああ、どっちも美味しいんですけど、なんか別かもしれない。
Oh, something different.  I wonder what it is.
おお、別物。なんすかね。
Mexican meat is kind of like Tasmanian beef, it feels like you're eating meat.
メキシコの肉ってなんかタスマニアンビーフみたいな、こう肉食べてるみたいな。
Ah, yes.  yes.  It tastes like red meat.   It
あ、はい。はい。赤身って感じですね。
's a lean steak, and I love that kind of meat.
赤みって感じのお肉でそういうステーキ大好きなんですよ。
Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.
うん。うん。うん。
But in Japan, they have thorns like this.
でも日本だとこう刺が入ってるじゃないですか。
Ah, the oil is quite beautiful.
ああ、なんか油がね、結構ま、美しいですね。
Yes, it's beautiful.  Yeah.  I see.   I ca
そう、美しいですよね。うん。そっか。
n't eat a lot.
なんかいっぱい食べられない。
Ah, that's true.  23
あ、確かに。23
pieces, I think that's okay.  Yes, yes, yes, yes.  Well, when I eat steak in Mexico,
枚でね、ちょっとそういうのはいいかなって。そう、そう、そう、そう。なん、僕メキシコでステーキとか食べると
[music] I don't mind eating
[音楽]
500g or so.
なんか500gとかも平気で。
No way, no way.  500%
無理、無理。500%
or something.  Oh, I see.  I see, I see.
とか。あ、そっか。そっか、そっか。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
そう、そう、そう、そう。
When I eat Japanese yakiniku with that feeling,
なんかその感覚で日本の焼肉食べるともう全然
500g is just not possible.   That's
500gなんて無理で。
right.  Oh, I see.
いですね。あ、そうなんですね。
[MUSIC]
[音楽]
Right.  Did you go for yakiniku this time? Yes, I did
そっか。今回は焼肉行きましたか?
.  I went.
行きました。行きました。
ah.  What was delicious? Was it the hami? It
ああ。何が美味しかったですか?ハミですか?
was the hami.
ハみですよね。
In the past, you could get kalbi, but
なんか昔はカルビとか行けたんですけど、
now it's skirt steak.
今もうハラミですね。
Yeah.  That's right.  It's pretty simple, but it's important.
うん。そうすね。割とさっぱりしてるけど重視でっていうね。
Yeah.  Yeah.  oh yeah.  That's about it.
うん。うん。そうそう。そんな感じです。
Japanese people love food, don't they?
食べ物好きっすよね、日本人ね。
Yeah.  Yes, yes, yes.
うん。そう、そう、そう。
I wonder what Urume has to say.  Ah, it's
結構なんかウルメがなんて言うんですかね。ア、アトラクションっていうか
not so much an attraction as it is one of
なんかね、その趣味のうちの1
everyone's hobbies.  Yeah.
みんなのね。うん。
When choosing a city, it's important to consider whether there are good restaurants there and how
街を選ぶってなった時もね、そのそこに美味しい料理屋さんがあるかどうかとか
many different countries' cuisines you can access.
ね、どれくらいの国の料理にアクセスできるかとかも大事になりますもんね。
Yeah.  I agree.
うん。そうですね。
Japan is a great place.
日本いいですよ。
Actually, today
実はね、あの、今日ね、ずっと日本いいですよってね、
I've been promoting Japan, saying how great it is.  Why don't you come back to Japan? It's delicious.
私は日本の宣伝をゆさんにしてたんです。日本に戻ってきたらどうですか?おいしいですよっていう。
yes.  It's waving.
そう。なびいてる。
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.   It's
そう、そう、そう、そう、そう。
trembling.  Yes, yes,
なびてますよ。そう、そう、
yes.  I see, I see.  So, well, Mexico and Japan, well, I came back from Mexico to Japan,
そう。そっか、そっか。じゃあ、まあ、メキシコと日本、ま、メキシコから日本に帰ってきて
yeah.  Yeah.
うん。うん。
Well, I ate a lot of different things.
食べたのは、ま、色々全部食べましたね。
yes.  I ate a variety of things.  So, yeah.  Yeah.
そう。色々食べました。で、うん。うん。
It's nothing special, but for example, when I think of breakfast,
なんか特別なことじゃないんですけど、例えば朝ご飯
I like natto rice or miso soup, and those kinds of things have really come to mind this time
つ取ってもなんか納豆ご飯とかお味噌汁とかま、ああいうのがすごく今回
.  I thought it was delicious.
なるほど。美味しいなって思いました。
Yeah.  I see.  I see.
うん。そっか。そっか。
Something simple.
なんか素朴なやつ。
Yeah.  Yeah.  A simple one.  Oh, that's nice.  Natto rice or shirasu and rice, for example.  That's nice.
うん。うん。素朴なやつ。あ、いいですよね。納豆ご飯とかシラスとご飯とかね。いいですよね。
Yes, yes, yes.  Like rice with raw egg on top.
そう、そう、そう。卵かけご飯とかもね。
ah.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.
ああ。うん。うん。うん。うん。
Oh, that's nice.
ああ、いいですね。
I don't think you can eat rice with raw egg on top if you're overseas.
海外だと多分卵かけご飯食べれないと思うんですよ。
Yeah.  Ah, it's a bit difficult from a satellite perspective.  Yeah.  Yeah.  yes.
うん。ああ、ちょっと衛星的に難しいな。うん。うん。そう。
Oh, that's right.  In Japan, that is.
あ、そうなんです。日本だとね。
Yeah.  Yeah.
うん。うん。
That might have been quite a joy this time.  Something like
それも結構今回嬉しかったかもしれない。なんか
that.  Yeah.  It's an egg.  You
うん。うん。卵だ。なんか食べる時に
might get a stomach ache when you eat it, but that can't be helped,
もしかしたらお腹痛くなるかもしれないけど、ま、しょうがないよねっていう
yeah.  There is no such feeling of anxiety.
うん。その不安感がない。
Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.   The
うん。うん。うん。
peace of mind that you won't get an upset stomach.  A sense of security.  Yeah.  surely.  surely.
安心感。安心感。うん。確かに。確かに。
Wow.   That
へえ。
's right.  yes.  So, we asked Yu-san to tell us all about Japanese food.  yes.  see you later.  bye bye.   see
そうなんですね。はい。ということで、あの、ゆさんに色々日本の食事のことを語っていただきました。はい。じゃあまたね。バイバイ。
you.  The blue sky is beautiful.
またね。青空が綺麗。
surely.
確かに。
So, what was the best thing you ate in Japan, or what would you like to eat? Please, um, leave a comment.   I
では皆さんは日本で食べて美味しかったもの、もしくは食べたいものは何ですか?是非、えっと、コメントください。
agree.  It would also be nice to have something you want to eat.
そうだね。あと食べたいものとかでもいいですね。
Yeah.  I agree.  yes.  Something I want to eat.  yes.  By the way, where is this?
うん。そうですね。はい。食べたいもの。そう。ちなみにここはどこですか?
Yes, this is it.  Osaka.
ここははい。大阪ですね。
Is this beautiful background in Osaka Kitahama? Kitahama.  Isn't this Kitahama?
北浜ですか?北浜。北浜じゃないですか?
What is this?
これは何だろう?
Um, I thought maybe I knew it.
えっと、私知ってんのかと思った。
There's some kind of library behind it, but what is it called? Shall we go and take a look?
なんか図書館が裏にあるんですけど、これはね、何でしたかね?ちょっと見に行きましょうか?
Yes.  Shall we go?  yes.
はい。行きましょうか。はい。
It's a complete mess.  Sorry.
全然グダグダです。すいません。
That's fine.   It's a
いいじゃないですか。
laid back kind of feeling.
そういうのんびりとした感じで。
yes.  Oh, right.  I went to Osaka for the first time a long time ago
はい。あ、そう。僕昔初めて大阪に
.  Maybe it's the first time.  Um,
うん。初めてでもないか。あの
yeah.  My parents moved to Osaka,
うん。両親が大阪に引っ越して
and when I decided to go there too, this was the first place we met up.
で僕もじゃあ大阪行こうってなった時に初めて待ち合わせしたのがここだったんです。
Oh, I see.  So,
あ、そうだったんですね。じゃ、
memories,
思い出の
huh?  This place is nice.
へえ。ここいいですよね。
Hey, take it easy.  quiet.
ね、のんびりしてていい。静か。
I can't believe it, there were
まさかね、第2
so few people there that it was hard to believe it was the second capital.
の都とは思えないぐらい人が少なくてね。
Yeah.  I agree.  It's easy to walk in.
うん。そうですね。歩きやすいし。
Osaka is great.  Osaka is great.  Yeah.   There are
大阪いいすね。大阪いいですよね。うん。
a lot of people from Tokyo, so places like this.   There are a
東京人多いからね、こういうとこね。
lot of Tokyo people in places like this.
こういうとこはね、東京人多いですよね。
yes.  I mean, even with cherry blossoms in bloom like that, there would probably be a lot of people there, like, wow, really?   I
そう。もうだ、あれぐらいの桜でもう多分人うわーってね、え、そうなんですか。
think they'll get together.
集まっちゃうと思う。
Well, there's skin there.  There's a river, there's a river.
え、だ、そこに皮あるんですよ。川、川があるんですよ。
That's right.  hey.  oh
そうね。ね。そう
yeah.  Well, that's a completely different topic, but
そう。なんか、あの、全然話変わっちゃうんですけど
yeah.  Yeah.  I've traveled to many places
うん。うん。いろんなとこ旅行して
.
はい。
I think the most important thing in a city is the river.
こう街で一番大事なのって川だと思うんですよ。
Ah, why? It's a town without a river.
あ、え、どうしてですか?川ない町。
Yeah.  Yeah.  I have lived there.
うん。うん。住んだことあります。
yes.
はい。
Doesn't it just feel a bit lacking? I just don't feel like going into the water.
なんか、なんか物足りなくないですか?なんかちょっと水に行きたくなりません。
Ah, but I was near the ocean, so I guess that was okay.  I see.  So you like rivers?
あ、でも私海の近くだったんで、それは大丈夫だったかな。そっか。じゃあ川が好きなんですね。
oh yeah.  Actually, I want to see some water.  Yeah.  Yeah.  Yeah.   I'm not
そう、そう。てかなんか水を見たいっていう。うん。うん。うん。
coming to Mexico.  Yeah.  Oh, I see.  It's nice to live near water.
メキシこないんでね。うん。あ、そうなんですね。水辺のね、周り住むのいいですよね。
That's nice.
いいですよね。
So what is this place?
じゃあここはさて何なんでしょうか。
What is it?
何なんでしょうか。
Is that so?  What does it say? Above,
んでしょうか。なんて書いてますか?上、
Oh, this is just to show you something.
あ、これ一応一応なんか見せるために。
Oh, I see, I see, I see.
あ、そっか、そっか、そっか。
Guess what? Yes.  Let's take a look.
何だと思います?はい。ちょっと見てみましょうか。
Yeah.  Ah, Osaka city center.
うん。あ、大阪市中央か。
[Music]
[音楽]
Well,
ま、
Tokaido means it's some kind of hall.
東海道ってことはなんかホールなんだ。
Ah, a hall.  Wow.  But it's a pretty old
あ、ホールか。へえ。でも結構昔の
building.  Yeah.  Hmm.
建物ですよね。うん。うーん。て
Ah, I'm glad the sky is blue.  That's nice.   It
ああ、青空出て良かったね。いいですね。
was cloudy just now.
さっきまで曇ってましたよね。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.  yes.
そう、そう、そう、そう。はい。
yes.  So now I'll
はい。ということでこれからまたあの
be streaming that again.   I'd
流します。
like to take a stroll around Osaka.
流して大阪を散歩したりしたいと思います。
see you later.  bye bye.
じゃあまたね。バイバイ。